ONUR EKER

Mobile Engineer

206-788-6778

yonureker@gmail.com

www.onureker.com

San Francisco, CA



After spending 10 years in digital marketing, I am now pursuing my dreams to become a software engineer. Recently, I have graduated from AppAcademy Software Engineering Track and I am currently exploring new opportunities in mobile app development. I am a passionate mobile engineer who never tires of challenging themselves and learning new things. I always strive for innovation yielding the highest possible efficiency of the code base

PROJECTS

Bart Live Mobile React Native, React Native Maps, Expo, Javascript, React Hooks

Live | Github

- Utilized BART API to query the real time estimated departure time of each train for every station in the BART system.
- Used React Native Map components to dynamically present active BART stations on Google Maps.
- Made use of Expo documentation for functionalities like fetching user location, image caching, splash / loading screens.

My Wallet React Native, React Navigation, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Javascript

Github

- Authored front-end and back-end authentication measures with BCrypt on the back-end and React Navigation on the front-end to ensure user privacy and autonomy.
- Learned how to create routes in Express.js, manipulating data in MongoDB and connecting a backend to frontend.

DeCrypt React Native, React Navigation, Firebase, Javascript, Expo

Github

- Created login, signup and profile screens with plain React Native components and implemented user authentication with a Firebase backend.
- Connected multiple auth methods (Facebook, Google etc.) to a user account with the help of Firebase documentation.

TaskRubyt Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, React.js, Redux, Webpack, Heroku

Live | Github

- Capstone project at AppAcademy. Designed and implemented database schema, application state, backend and frontend routes.
- Implemented CRUD and REST using Rails Routing for the back end and ReactRouter for
- Augmented standard RESTful routes with customized API to provide tailored data to a presentational slice of the Redux.js store from Postgres to feed the Redux cycle.

WORK EXPERIENCES

React Native Intern

Performance Marketing Manager

Affiliate Marketing Manager

Affiliate Marketing Manager

Online Marketing Specialist

Content Marketing Specialist (Contract)

Online Marketing Specialist

BitBroker Labs | 2020 - Current

TaskRabbit | 2018 - 2019

Tripping.com | 2017 - 2018

TripAdvisor | 2015 - 2016

Getty Images | 2013 - 2014

Microsoft Inc. | 2013 - 2013

eBay Inc. | 2010 - 2012

SKILLS

Technical

JavaScript/Ruby

React, React Native, Redux

Node.js. Rails. Express.js, Firebase

PostgreSQL, MongoDB

HTML5, CSS3

REST, GraphQL

Object-oriented design

Professional

Strong analytical skills

Project management

Desire to learn

Attention to detail

Effective communication

Team player

Strong problem solver

Excellent time management

EDUCATION

Software Engineering

AppAcademy 2019

BA - Economics

Bogazici University 2004 - 2010

LANGUAGES

English (Fluent)

Turkish (Native)

INTERESTS



github.com/yonureker



linkedin.com/in/onureker